Uh President Trump on Air Force One
yesterday [clears throat]
confirming the US intervened in the yen
on Friday, the first foreign currency
intervention by the US government in 15
years.
>> We have a good relationship with Japan.
We're very strong, very, very strong
financially.
And they are, you know, they have a
weakening yen
and they wanted a little bit of help and
we're always there for Japan. Japan's
been
very good to us.
>> Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent also
confirming the intervention in a tweet
saying it supports steps to quote
correct the substantial undervaluation
of the yen, counter disorderly yen
movements, and saying the US will not
hesitate to intervene again.
It was unclear how much the US
intervened. There was that Reuters photo
of Bessent's notepad at the Friday
cabinet meeting said to do buy Japanese
yen 5 to 10 billion dollars.
I don't think it was seen by reporters
by accident. I should hope not anyway.
Reuters reporting this morning the Bank
of Japan data suggests the Japanese
intervention on its own, that is without
the US, may have totaled around 37
billion dollars. The yen rallied sharply
on Friday's intervention from the dollar
buying 164 yen down to it buying 156 or
157 yen this morning. Global economist
Carl Weinberg says he thinks Japan has
drawn a line in the sand around 160 to
the dollar but it cautions the
intervention doesn't work on its own. He
told me over the weekend, "For currency
intervention to work, it usually has to
be supported by some policy
intervention. For example, an interest
rate hike." He was surprised the BOJ had
not done that to this point.